grandtheftwiki.com 2019-03-31

# Grand Theft Wiki:Privacy Policy - Grand Theft Wiki, the GTA wiki

Grand Theft Wiki is a website to provide and share information about Grand Theft Auto games. Everything we do is to enable us to help provide this service. 

This Privacy Policy is here so you understand how your personal data is used on Grand Theft Wiki, and help you understand your rights. 

## Summary

Grand Theft Wiki is a public wiki, meaning that any content uploaded can be accessed by anybody. This includes all edits to articles, your user page, talk pages and other pages, and all files uploaded. The change history of all files and pages is also publicly accessible. 

For this reason, we recommend you do not share personal information on the site, except what you would like to share on your own user page. Do not add anything you would not want everyone to see. For your profile page, displaying your name, age and location is good; website and email address is up to you; but telephone number and postal address is discouraged. 

We collect some other information from you when you use Grand Theft Wiki, so we can continue to run and improve the site. This is done for logging and understanding our users visits to our website, for identifying technical problems, for providing advertisements, and for providing a richer experience on the site. This can happen when you visit a page, create an account, make an edit, participate in our social media, or contact us. 

We are committed to: 

  * Only using your data for the purposes you have consented to
  * Explaining how your information may be used or shared in this Privacy Policy
  * Using reasonable measures to keep your information secure
  * Never selling your personal account data or sharing it with third parties for marketing purposes. 
  * Retaining your data for the shortest possible time that is consistent with maintaining, understanding, and improving Grand Theft Wiki, and our obligations under law.

## Personal Data

There are several types of personal data that we might hold: 

**1\. Usage Data**

When you visit Grand Theft Wiki, some usage data may be collected. Usage data relates to monitoring usage of this website. Usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. 

The source of the usage data is our analytics tracking system. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services. 

**2\. Account Data**

If you choose to create an account with Grand Theft Wiki, you may choose to share some personal information. We only store what you choose to share, which may include your name and email address. 

The account data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website. 

You can review your account data at Special:Preferences

**3\. Wiki Data**

When you edit a page on Grand Theft Wiki, that data will be publicly available. 

This includes the pages that you have edited, Talk pages, your user profile page, and any files uploaded. For each of these, the full history of changes is usually available, by clicking on the “History” tab. You can view your full history of edits at Special:MyContributions. 

You may choose to provide personal information on your user profile page, which will be publicly available. This is entirely your choice and is not required to use the site. You can view your user page at Special:MyPage. 

Any data shared will be processed and backed-up for the purpose of operating and securing our website. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business. 

**4\. Notification Data**

You can choose to receive notifications of changes from Grand Theft Wiki by email. All notifications are opt-in. You can review your notification preferences at Special:Preferences. You can review your watchlist at Special:EditWatchlist. 

We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters. This notification data may be processed for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications or newsletters. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract. 

**5\. Correspondence Data**

If you communicate with us, we may process the content of that communication. If you use a contact form on the site, we may also process some metadata associated with the communication. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business and communications with users. 

## Sharing Data

We may disclose your Usage Data to the companies that help us operate our website, including those that provide our hosting, monitoring, analytics, advertising, networking and security. 

We may disclose your email address to the companies that help us provide our email communications, such as notifications and newsletters. Each such third party will act as a data controller or data processor in relation to the enquiry data that we supply to it; and upon contacting you, each such third party will supply to you a copy of its own privacy policy, which will govern that third party's use of your personal data. 

In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out here, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. 

## Storing & Deleting Data

The hosting, monitoring, backup and email facilities for our website are situated in the US, Europe and UK. The European Commission has made an "adequacy decision" with respect to the data protection laws of each of these countries. Transfers to each of these countries will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. 

You acknowledge that personal data that you submit for publication through our website or services may be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use (or misuse) of such personal data by others. 

Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes. Data stored in backups will be securely held, but may take longer to be removed. 

We may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. 

In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this policy, we may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. 

## Cookies

We use cookies on Grand Theft Wiki. These are small pieces of text data, stored in your browser, that store information sent to/from the site, in between visits to pages on our site. 

For example, cookies are used to tell us that you are logged in, what your preferences are, and provide Usage Data to our analytics and advertising services. The range of cookies that we may use include: Google Analytics, Google AdSense, Google AdExchange, Google Tag Manager, Avocet, PulsePoint, Teads, Skimlinks, Monetizer 101, ComScore, Crazy Egg, Facebook Audience, Google Analytics Audience, 

Almost all websites use cookies in some way or another, and every page you visit in those sites writes cookies to your computer and receives them back from it. Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies. 

You can set your browser to block or alert you about these cookies, but some parts of the site will not then work. For more information, please see [ <http://cookiepedia.co.uk/all-about-cookies> Cookiepedia] 

## Cookies used by our service providers

Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website. 

We use Google Analytics and Comscore to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics and Comscore gather information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google's privacy policy is available at: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>. Comscore’s privacy policy is available at <https://www.comscore.com/About-comScore/Privacy-Policy>. 

We publish Google AdSense interest-based advertisements on our website. These are tailored by Google to reflect your interests. To determine your interests, Google will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the web using cookies. 

You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). 

You can also opt out of the AdSense partner network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative's multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). 

However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained. To ensure that an opt-out is maintained in respect of a particular browser, you may wish to consider using the Google browser plug-ins available at: <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996>. 

## Your Rights

You have a number of rights under data protection law. For example, these include: 

  * the right to access;
  * the right to rectification;
  * the right to erasure;
  * the right to restrict processing;
  * the right to object to processing;
  * the right to data portability;
  * the right to complain to a supervisory authority
  * the right to withdraw consent.

These rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our policy here. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights. 

Some of these rights can be exercised via Special:Preferences. For anything else, please contact data [at] grandtheftwiki [dot] com 

## Other points

Please do not supply any other person's personal data to us, unless we prompt you to do so. 

We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website. You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy. 

We may notify you of changes to this policy by email or through the notification system on our website. 

For more information, contact data [at] grandtheftwiki [dot] com
